# **Network Engineer**

# **Network Engineer - HCL America Inc**

Columbus, IN - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/a12799945751e9e8

Network Architect with over 10+ years of progressive experience seeking a position where my logical, technical, and troubleshooting skills can be used to improve the reliability and usability of the information technology infrastructure.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Network Engineer**

HCL America Inc - Columbus, IN - July 2016 to Present

Current working as a network engineer responsible for designing and installing WAN and LAN solutions to diverse businesses around the world. Technologies include Viptela SDWAN, Cisco routers and switches, Cisco Prime and APIC, Cisco and Meraki enterprise and industrial wireless.

#### **Network Security Administrator**

Ghost Systems, LLC - Reno, NV - September 2013 to June 2016

Responsible for Designing, Securing, and Managing local and remote networks consisting of Cisco, Meraki, Dell, HP and other networking and server equipment as well as Shoretel VIOP phones.

Acted as an IT Consultant for local businesses providing security assessments, technical support, security advice, and managed IT services.

Assisted in developing proprietary security centric devices and software for future use as well as developed strategy for providing Managed Security Services Such as network monitoring, secure DNS service, threat analytics, and incident and triage response.

### **Tactical Network Engineer, Communications Security Manager**

US Army - Reno, NV - July 2011 to August 2013

Responsible for planning, installing, and troubleshooting tactical networks with 32 nodes capable of supporting 2000+ users with secure and non-secure voice, data, video teleconference, and ISR services. As the Communications Security Manager, responsible for maintaining and distributing encryption keys in order to provide transmission and data encryption.

Developed troubleshooting guides for communications assets to include satellite assets, LOS assets, Cisco routers, switches, Call managers and firewalls.

Acted as Network Technician responsible for planning, implementing and securing large networks in tactical environments.

#### **IT Support Administrator**

Sierra, Nevada - Reno, NV - May 2009 to June 2011

Responsible for providing tier 2 troubleshooting support to users and executives on workstation, server, VOIP, and networking systems and applications. Collaborated with other IT sections to deploy, secure, maintain, and recover workstations and servers.

Built and maintained budget tracking procedures for a hardware budget in excess of \$750,000 for three regions and 31 locations.

Maintained hundreds of laptops, desktops and servers in an high paced corporate environment using programs such as Microsoft System Center Configuration Manager 2012, Windows 7 Enterprise, Lotus Notes, Symantec End Point, Symantec PGP, and several design and development programs.

# **Information Systems Coordinator**

Hydro-Gear - San Diego, CA - May 2007 to April 2009

Network\Systems architect responsible for 99.9% uptime standard Participated in BCP (Business Continuity Planning) meetings and provided technological solutions for the company's business strategies

- Wrote technical documentation and proposals for management and non IT personnel
   Familiarity with Sarbanes-Oxley in how it relates to IT systems and provided documentation to maintain compliance
- Implemented and maintained company's system and physical security for multiple sites
- Provided Cisco VoIP telephone training in multiple sites
- Researched and provided recommendations for new technologies, based on business requirements
- Provided detailed monthly reports to direct supervisor regarding project status, current issues, and upcoming projects
- Provided 24/7 support for Servers, VoIP phone system, network infrastructure

#### **EDUCATION**

# **B.S.** in Information Systems Technology in Information Systems Technology Southern Illinois University

SKILLS

Cisco (8 years), DNS (2 years), firewalls. (2 years), LAN (1 year), wireless. (1 year)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Software Skills:

Active Directory, DNS, DHCP, TCP/IP, RADIUS/IAS

Microsoft Office

Windows Server

Microsoft Visio

SolarWinds Orion

Performance Monitor, Configuration Manager, Traffic Analyzer

**QRadar SIEM** 

# Log Aggregation

# Cisco Network Skills:

- Cisco Catalyst Switches
- Cisco Nexus/Data Center Switches
- Cisco Wide Area Application Services
- Cisco ASA Firewalls
- Cisco Wireless LAN Controller
- Cisco Access Points
- Cisco Prime Infrastructure
- Cisco Integrated Services Routers
- BGP, EIGRP, Routing Protocols
- MPLS, P2P WAN Infrastructures
- T1, DS3, Ethernet Circuits
- VLANs, QoS, Netflow, Link Aggregation, Policy Based Routing